### LISA BUGAYONG

# E-LEARNING STRATEGIST PASSIONATE EDUCATOR TRAINING PROGRAM DESIGNER



949-351-1697

Lisa.bugayong@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/lisa-bugayong-b17301138/

Igniting workforce performance by providing training tools that empower employees to reach new heights

Utilize training expertise and clear communication customized to meet any corporate environment.

- Leverage strong teaching education and experience to create course content that captures the learner's interest.
- Design e-Learning processes that deliver technical training excellence. Create animation, audio, and video training modules to address workforce or technology training requirements.
- > **Technology:** Articulate Storyline, Moodle, Cornerstone, Animated PowerPoint- Video, Audacity, Camtasia, FrameMaker, Lectora

# **PROVEN STRENGTHS**

E-Learning Process Designer
Clear/Concise Communicator
Technical Training Programs
Quick to Learn New Programs
Multi-Industry E-Learning Courses
Positive Learning Environment
Designer of E-learning Courses
Conscientious Trainer/Instructor

### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

### TECHNICAL WRITER/DOCUMENT CONTROLLER | KODELLA, IRVINE, CA | 2021 – 2022

**Operations Department** 

- Reviewed and edited documents such as job descriptions and the Kodella Employee Handbook.
- Created the Guidelines for Technical Recruiters.

**Development Department** 

- Helped implement a plan for creating a template for the User Acceptance training.
- Created the Agile and Scrum Guidelines, and the Template Usage Guidelines for Development.

Sales Department

- Helped the Sales VP organize and write his department's new vision plan.
- Created the Role Handbook for the Business Development Representative.

Training, Education, and Documentation Department

- Created training videos using Camtasia for technical writers to learn document formatting and how to use Google Drive.
- Created guidelines such as Guide to Templates and Forms; Guide to Google Permissioning; and Documentation Style, Usage, and Formatting Guide.
- Generated a vision plan and overall goals for a new documentation system. Wrote the implementation plan for this vision.
  - Restructured the company's Google Drive to set up a Documentation Management System (DMS) rather than purchasing one due to budget constraints.
  - Collaborated with the Operations department to define Google groups for drive permissioning.
  - Met with managers to discuss the vision plan's implications for their departments. Obtained their approval for the Google groups necessary for their departments.
  - Re-designed the Documentation Request form and created an approval process to be tracked on the ClickUp project management software.

# INSTRUCTIONAL DESIGNER | HELPMATES - 6-MONTH CONTRACT, MAZDA NORTH AMERICAN OPERATIONS, IRVINE, CA | 2020

Hired to help create soft training for an Optimal Leadership Training program for new employees or those newly promoted to a people manager position.

- Using the given objectives, researched, developed, and designed four one-hour facilitated classes for phase 1 of the Optimal Leadership Training program. The classes included Effective Communication, Delegation, Difficult Conversations, Time Management, and Partnering with Your Manager.
  - Created all classes in PowerPoint using the Mazda template and color scheme. Also ensured that they
    contained the appropriate re-branding terminology approved by Human Resources Vice President.
  - Led design review meetings for the training classes and adapted them per the subject matter expert's input.

# INSTRUCTIONAL DESIGNER | HELPMATES - 6-MONTH CONTRACT WITH RAND TECHNOLOGY, IRVINE, CA | 2019

Brought in to design an e-learning training program for new employees to learn the company's business software. The program consisted of 35 lessons specific to purchasing and sales department deliverables. In addition, created two training classes that outlined new sales and purchasing processes.

- Quickly gained insight into the company's processes and procedures while simultaneously delivering informative e-learning courses.
- Successfully implemented a Learning Management System (LMS) from the ground up that tracked employee class attendance and uploaded all training files into the LMS.
- Oversaw all aspects of training material development, including adding animation and audio to the PowerPoint slides.
- Scripted and recorded all audio; edited it for noise, tone, and inflection. Made all requested changes by inserting audio in the track instead of re-recording it.
- Created training workshops; developed accurate instructional videos; devised quizzes for each section.
- Taught the Quality Control Manager and IT Project Manager how to produce training using a quick reference guide that I created. The guide discussed creating videos and audio files, and adding audio and animations to slides in PowerPoint.
- Taught a training class that I created to a new manager to ensure that he understood the new purchase price variance process.

# TECHNICAL WRITER, TRAINING | MSC SOFTWARE - PART TIME, NEWPORT BEACH, CA | 2009 TO 2016

- Created numerous training videos using Camtasia that explained the usage of various commands for SimXpert and Patran software.
- Updated online help documentation for SimXpert geometry commands using FrameMaker.
- Develop training classes and lecture notes/workshops for engineering software packages using PowerPoint. Courses ranged from two days to a week.
- Edited training classes for grammar, professional style, and accuracy of examples and case studies.
- Modified instructor-led training courses for e-learning applications. This modification was done using Lectora and included adding quizzes, certification tests, animation, and audio integration.
- Co-authored the e-learning guidelines on animation and audio component processes. Wrote the guidelines after attending meetings where key decisions about the e-learning format were discussed.
- Served as the point of contact for questions regarding new processes and helped ensure all department members learned new procedures.

# DESIGN ENGINEER | McDonnel Douglas (Boeing), Huntington Beach, CA | 1994 to 1996

• Designed components used in the Pressurized Mating Adapter on the International Space Station.

### **TUTORING EXPERIENCE**

# TUTOR | ALOHA TUTORING CENTER, LAKE FOREST, CA | 2018 TO 2019

Tutored mathematics, reading, and writing to elementary school students.

- Ensured students understood and retained course content.
- Assisted in organizing, filing, grading, and planning courses curriculum.

### TUTOR | KUMON MATH AND READING CENTER, RANCHO SANTA MARGARITA, CA | 2016 TO 2019

Tutored reading and mathematics to kindergarten through high school students.

• Developed reading lessons and utilized a focused approach to capture student attention and course content retention.

# **EDUCATION/CERTIFICATES**

- B.S., Aerospace Engineering California State Polytechnic University, Pomona, CA, 1991
- Preliminary Single Subject Credential in Mathematics Chapman University, Orange, CA, 1996
- A.A., Business Administration Fullerton Community College, Fullerton, CA, 1988
- ATD Adult Learning Certificate This program included eight application-based courses, 2020
  - Theory to practice
  - Theory to completion
  - Motivating and engaging adults
  - Applying learning in workplace
  - Assessing learning needs
  - Developing learning content
  - Extending the classroom
  - Learning technologies
- Coursera Certificate: Instructional Design Foundations and Applications with concentration using ADDIE University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 2019
- Articulate Storyline Essentials Certificate IconLogic, 2020
- Editing Mastery: How to Edit Writing to Perfection LinkedIn Learning, 2023